Guide to the Brooklyn Arts Council Folk Arts collection CBHM.0002
Center for Brooklyn History
- Series 5: Folk Feet: Celebrating Traditional Dance in Brooklyn
  - Sub-series 5.1: Program Files
    - Funding, Rockefeller Brothers, 2007-2009 (Box 50, Folder 20)
    - Funding, Sources, circa 2003-2009 (Box 50, Folder 21)
    - Printed Matter, circa 2003-2009 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Oversize Posters, 2004 (Box 97, Folder 2)
    - Printed Matter, 2004 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Oversize Posters, 2005 (Box 97, Folder 3)
    - Printed matter, 2005 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Oversize Posters, 2006 (Box 97, Folder 4)
    - Printed Matter, 2006 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Oversize Posters, 2007 (Box 97, Folder 5)
    - Printed Matter, 2007 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Printed Matter, 2008 (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - Printed Matter, 2009 (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - Non BAC Dance, circa 2003-2007 (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - Footbridge Video Project, 2007 (Box 51, Folder 9)
    - Contracts and Check Requests, 2004 (Box 51, Folder 10)
    - Contracts and Check Requests, 2005 (Box 51, Folder 11)
    - Contracts and Check Requests, 2006 (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Contracts and Check Requests, 2007 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Contracts and Check Requests, 2008 (Box 52, Folder 3-4)
    - Contracts and Check Requests, 2009 (Box 52, Folder 5-6)
    - Contracts, RESTRICTED, 2004-2006 (Box 100, Folder 5)
  - Sub-series 5.2: Audiovisual
    The Audiovisual sub-series includes interviews with artists participating in Folk Feet programs or who represent dance traditions documented by the project. Some were conducted at Folk Feet events. See listing below for interviewee, date and format.
    2004
    Mamadon Dahone, Ivory Coast, 1/6/2004, cassette tape
    Donald Golden, Irish Dancer, 1/9/2004, cassette tape
    Eleni Drogaris, Greek folk dancer, 1/9/2004, cassette tape
    Cliff Matins, Native American Hoop Dance, 1/23/2004, cassette tape
    Euston James, Trinidadian limbo, 3/23/2004, cassette tape
    Gloria Wilson, Conjunto NM, Panamanian, 11/7/2004, cassette tape
    Renee Flowers, Gowanus Wildcats, 12/15/2004, cassette tape
    Mozghan Motamedi, Iranian/Persian Dance, 12/28/2004, cassette tape
    2004-05
    Anup Kumar Das, 2004-05, CD
    2005
    Joe Dwyer, Irish stepdance, 1/7/2005, cassette tape
    Yemenite American Association, 2/3/2005, cassette tape
    Daiana Castillo, Dominican, 3/29/2005, cassette tape
    Dario of Alianza, 4/2/2005, cassette tape
    Isaac Gutwilik, 5/13/2005, cassette tape
    Leonardo Dominguez, Merengue, 5/15/2005, cassette tape
    Najwa Adra, Yemeni dance, 7/13/2005, cassette tape
    Rita Silver, Afro-Brazilian dance, 7/19/2005, cassette tape
    Ahmed Alkodina, 7/19/2005, cassette tape
    Yitzhak Levy, Awami, 7/28/2005, 2 casstte tapes
    Mohamed Bechar, 8/23/2005, 2 cassette tapes
    Antonia Guerrero, Mexican conchero dance, 11/15/2005, cassette tape
    2006
    Field interviews, video, VHS tape
    Tiny Love/Rozvan Gorea, Uprock/B-boy (Romanian), 1/4/2006, 2 cassette tapes
    Darren Carr, Irish traditional, 6/1/2006, cassette tape
    2007
    Renee Flowers and Ralph "King Uprock" Casonova, 2/2/2007, 2 CDs
    2008
    Shock-a-Lock, 8/6/2008, DVD
    Sady Sullivan, Marie-Basse Wiles, Irina Roizin, Brooklyn Historical Society Collaboration, 2008, DVD (audio only)
    Sady Sullivan, Carlos Vasquez, Shock-a-Lock, Donny Golden, Brooklyn Historical Society Collaboration, 8/12/2008, DVD (audio only)
    2008-2009
    Traditional Dance in Detail, demonstrations and interviews: Christafo Madimenos, Euston James, Yassar Darwish, Linda Sarsour, Nadia Dieudonne, Melinda Gonzalez, (DVDs)
    Traditional Dance in Brooklyn, demonstrations and interviews: Razvan Gorea, Ralph Casnova, Rita Silva, Vongku Pak, Renee Flowers, Gowanus Wildcats, DVD
    Dancing Detail, demonstrations and interviews: Porter, Matias, DVD
    2009
    Aeilushi Mistry, Indian/Bhartnatyan/Garba/Raas, interview 2, February 6, 2009, DVD (audio only)
    Aeilushi Mistry, November 5, 2009, CD
    - Event Photographs and Slides, 2003-2006 (Box 53, Binder 1)
    - Video and Audio, 2003 (Box 54, Item 1-10)
    - Photographs, 2003 (Box 54, Item 11-12)
    - Video, 2004 (Box 54, Item 13-17)
    - Video, 2004 (Box 55, Item 1-11)
    - Video, 2004 (Box 56, Item 1)
    - Audio, 2004 (Box 56, Item 2-10)
    - Photographs, 2004 (Box 56, Item 11-15)
    - Video, 2005 (Box 56, Item 16-23)
    - Audio, 2005 (Box 56, Item 24-27)
    - Audio, 2005 (Box 57, Item 1-11)
    - Photographs, 2005 (Box 57, Item 12-28)
    - Video, 2006 (Box 57, Item 29-35)
    - Video, 2006 (Box 58, Item 1-9)
    - Audio, 2006 (Box 58, Item 10-16)
    - Photographs, 2006 (Box 58, Item 17-25)
    - Video, 2007 (Box 58, Item 26-35)
    - Audio, 2007 (Box 58, Item 36-37)
    - Photographs, 2007 (Box 58, Item 38-50)
    - Video, 2008 (Box 58, Item 51-66)
    - Audio, 2008 (Box 58, Item 67-69)
    - Photographs, 2008 (Box 58, Item 70-74)
    - Video, 2008-2009 (Box 59, Item 1-18)
    - Video, 2009 (Box 59, Item 19-23)
    - Audio, 2009 (Box 59, Item 24-26)
    - Photographs, 2009 (Box 59, Item 27-35)
    - Unidentified Multimedia, circa 2003-2009 (Box 59, Item 36-54)
    - Artist Interviews on BCAT's Brooklyn Review, Video, 2004-2005 (Box 60, Item 1-9)
      List of participating artists included in Box 60.
    - Grant Support Materials, circa 2003-2009 (Box 61, Item 1-20)
- Series 6: Folk Made
  Folk Made was a project to connect traditional craft artists working in Brooklyn who were interested in marketing and exhibiting their work. Collaborating with the New York Foundation on the Arts, Folk Arts conducted a survey to gauge interest and collected program files on possible artists. Interviews with various artists were recorded but the project was ultimately not funded.
  Program Files include correspondence and notes from Folk Arts attempting to secure artists to participate in the program. Artist files include biographies, notes, promotional materials, examples of work, and interview information. The Audiovisual sub-series includes cassettes with artist interviews. Slides and print photographs were collected during the survey and show artwork from the artists represented in the interviews and program files.
  - Sub-series 6.1: Program Files
    - Call for Artists, 2004 (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - NYFA New York Creates Project, 2004 (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - Contacts, 2004 (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - Contacts, Possible Sources, 2004 (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - Data Sheets, Contracts, Permissions, 2004 (Box 62, Folder 5)
    - African, 2004 (Box 62, Folder 6)
    - Carribean, 2004 (Box 62, Folder 7)
    - Jewish, 2004 (Box 62, Folder 8)
    - Occupational, 2004 (Box 62, Folder 9)
    - Russian, 2004 (Box 62, Folder 10)
    - Aldaverdov, Leonid: Tapestry, Copper Plates, 2004 (Box 62, Folder 11)
    - Belenky, Ilya: Marquetry, 2004 (Box 62, Folder 12)
    - Bell, Sandra: Carnival Costume Maker, 2004 (Box 62, Folder 13)
    - Brown, Peche: Quilter, 2004 (Box 62, Folder 14)
    - Cox, Emelda: Quilter, 2004 (Box 62, Folder 15)
    - Dellocono, Jimmy: Giglio, 2004 (Box 62, Folder 16)
    - Hall, Virginia: Quilter, 2004 (Box 62, Folder 17)
    - Hawks International Carnival Costume Maker, 2004 (Box 62, Folder 18)
    - Jewish Folk Craft Guild, 2004 (Box 62, Folder 19)
    - Komolafe, Isaac: Woodcarver, 2004 (Box 62, Folder 20)
    - Kuchynkas, Irene: Decorated Eggs, 2004 (Box 62, Folder 21)
    - Rodriguez, Gloria: Pen and Ink Cartoons, 2004 (Box 62, Folder 22)
    - Rozenblyum, Rudolf: Copper Reliefs, 2004 (Box 62, Folder 23)
    - Ruiz, Natalio "Junior" Tirado: Drum Maker, 2004 (Box 62, Folder 24)
    - Soloveyev, Matvey and Tsypina, Nina: Shell and Metal Art, 2004 (Box 62, Folder 25)
    - Thomas, Cheryl: Gourd Instruments, 2004 (Box 62, Folder 26)
    - Vaynshelboym, Issar: Painter, 2004 (Box 62, Folder 27)
    - Wallace, George: Sign Painter, 2004 (Box 62, Folder 28)
    - Xun, Ye: Flour Dough Artist, 2004 (Box 62, Folder 29)
  - Sub-series 6.2: Audiovisual
    Foly Kolane, Nigerian Fabric Arts
    Rudolf Rozenblum, Copper Plate Artist
    Konstanio Pylarinos, Byzantine Woodcarver
    Emelda Cox, Quilter
    Peche Brown, Quilter
    Richard Amoah
    Lonid Aldaverdov, Tapestry, Copper Plates
    Louise Fisher Cozzi, Quilter
    Chief Komofalfe, Woodcarver
    Jimmy Dellacono, Giglio
    Vera Sokolow, Jewish Craft Artist
    Xun, Ye, Flour Dough Artist (2 cassettes)
    Yushao Hua, Palm Animals
    William Del Pilar, Guitar Maker
    - Interviews, 2004 (Box 62, Item 1-15)
    - Photographs and Slides, circa 1991-2004 (Box 63, Binder 1)
- Series 7: Half the Sky Festival: Brooklyn Women in Traditional Performance
  Half the Sky Festival: Brooklyn Women in Traditional Performance was created and produced by Kay Turner, Folk Arts Director at the Brooklyn Arts Council. The festival, which was held from April-June 2012 consisted of six weeks of concerts, panels and workshops featuring music, dance, narrative, verbal arts, and ritual traditions. Events included lullabies, folk tales, wedding songs, and social dances. The festival name comes from a Chinese proverb, "women hold up half the sky," and is used as a stepping off point for recognizing that despite the 50% statistic alluded to in the phrase, women's traditional performances are still often segregated and domesticated.
  Program Files include project contacts, fieldwork, media, notes, programming details, project history and scheduling. Promotional materials include clippings, mailers, fliers, and email sign-up sheets. Budget files and funding information is also included. Program Files also include consent forms and logs for participant interviews. Audiovisual materials include event documentation and interviews. Photographs are digital.
  Half the Sky Festival events included:
  Gender and Diaspora: Conflicts and Resolutions. AIR Gallery, April 21, 2012.
  Keeping Boundaries/Breaking Barriers. Brooklyn Historical Society, April 22, 2012.
  The Sweetest Song. A capella vocal concert. Brooklyn Public Library Dweck Center, April 28, 2012.
  High Strung Women. Jalopy Theater, May 10, 2012.
  The Home Altar as Ex-Voto: Living with the Sacred. John D. Calandra Italian American Institute, May 8, 2012.
  A Woman Upfront Benefit Concert and Reception. Roulette, May 9, 2012.
  Folk Feet Females. Kumble Theater, Long Island University, May 12, 2012.
  Bay Mayn Mames Shtibele: The Women's Art of Yiddish Folksong. Center for Jewish History, May 14, 2012.
  Jazz Women Fusing Forms Concert. BAM Cafe, May 18, 2012.
  Cinderella in the Arab World. Brooklyn Public Library, Bay Ridge branch, May 31, 2021.
  Girls Hit the Streets. The Actors Fund Arts Center, June 2, 2012.
  Women's Rites and Rituals: The Art of Transformation. Congregation B'nai Avraham Mikvah, June 3, 2012.
  Drum it Down. Brooklyn Public Library, Flatbush branch, June 5, 2012.
  Circle, Shimmy, Sway Dance Circle. Brooklyn Bridge Park, June 9, 2012.
  Bachelorette Bash. American Association of Crimean Turks Center and Mosque, June 10, 2012.
  Participants included:
  Muna Abdel Azziz
  Maha Attieh
  Zeinab Bader
  Riham Barghouti
  Trina Basu
  Mary Bielski
  Tamara Chernyakhouvsky
  Nijmat Falasteen
  Annie Ferdous
  Omheah Hamdi
  Uriye Hanim
  Aeilushi Mistry
  Kaina Quenga
  Bhagmatti Ragbir
  Shobana Ram
  Sandhya Rao
  Amanda Seigel
  Rajalakshmi Shankar
  Shoshana Tubi
  Baba Umpho
  Maria Yoon
  - Sub-series 7.1: Program Files
    - Contacts, 2012 (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - Contacts, Performing Artists, 2012 (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - Fieldwork, 2012 (Box 64, Folder 3)
    - Media, 2012 (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - General Notes, 2012 (Box 64, Folder 5)
    - Participation, 2012 (Box 64, Folder 6)
    - Programming Details, 2012 (Box 64, Folder 7)
    - Project History, 2012 (Box 64, Folder 8)
    - Scheduling, 2012 (Box 64, Folder 9)
    - Budget, 2012 (Box 64, Folder 10)
    - Check Requests, 2012 (Box 64, Folder 11-12)
    - Costs, 2012 (Box 64, Folder 13)
    - Funding, JP Morgan Bank, 2012 (Box 64, Folder 14)
    - Funding, MetLife, 2012 (Box 64, Folder 15)
    - Funding, NEA, 2012 (Box 64, Folder 16)
    - Funding, Violet Jabara Charitable Trust, 2012 (Box 64, Folder 17)
    - Publicity, Email List, 2012 (Box 64, Folder 18)
    - Publicity, Program Mailer, 2012 (Box 64, Folder 19)
    - Publicity, Misc., 2012 (Box 64, Folder 20)
    - Consent Forms, 2012 (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - Events, Gender and Diaspora, 2012 (Box 65, Folder 2)
    - Events, Keeping Boundaries / Breaking Barriers, 2012 (Box 65, Folder 3)
    - Events, The Sweetest Song, 2012 (Box 65, Folder 4)
    - Events, The Home Altar as Ex-Voto: Living With the Sacred, Lecture by Kay Turner, 2012 (Box 65, Folder 5)
    - Events, A Woman Upfront Benefit Concert and Reception, 2012 (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - Events, High Strung Woman, Concert, 2012 (Box 65, Folder 7)
    - Events, Folk Feet Females, 2012 (Box 65, Folder 8)
    - Events, Bay mayn mame's shtibele, The Women's Art of Yiddish Folksong, 2012 (Box 65, Folder 9)
    - Events, Jazz Women Fusing Forms, 2012 (Box 65, Folder 10)
    - Events, Cinderella in the Arab World, 2012 (Box 65, Folder 11)
    - Events, Girls Hit the Streets, 2012 (Box 65, Folder 12)
    - Events, Women's Rites and Rituals, 2012 (Box 65, Folder 13)
    - Events, Drum it Down, 2012 (Box 65, Folder 14)
    - Events, Circle, Shimmy, Sway, 2012 (Box 65, Folder 15)
    - Events, Bachelorette Bash, 2012 (Box 65, Folder 16)
    - Interview Consent Forms, 2012 (Box 65, Folder 17)
    - Interview Logs, Abdelaziz, Muna, 2012 (Box 65, Folder 18)
    - Interview Logs, Ahieh, Maha, 2012 (Box 65, Folder 19)
    - Interview Logs, Bader, Zeinab, 2012 (Box 65, Folder 20)
    - Interview Logs, Basu, Trina, 2012 (Box 65, Folder 21)
    - Interview Logs, Chernyakhousky, Tamara, 2012 (Box 65, Folder 22)
    - Interview Logs, Ferdous, Annie, 2012 (Box 65, Folder 23)
    - Interview Logs, Hamdi, Omneah, 2012 (Box 65, Folder 24)
    - Interview Logs, Hanim, Uriye, 2012 (Box 65, Folder 25)
    - Interview Logs, Mistry, Aeilushi, 2012 (Box 65, Folder 26)
    - Interview Logs, Ragbir, Bhagmati, 2012 (Box 65, Folder 27)
    - Interview Logs, Ram, Shobana, 2012 (Box 65, Folder 28)
    - Interview Logs, Rao, Sandhya, 2012 (Box 65, Folder 29)
    - Interview Logs, Seigel, Amanda, 2012 (Box 65, Folder 30)
    - Interview Logs, Shankar, Rajalakshmi, 2012 (Box 65, Folder 31)
    - Interview Logs, Tubi, Shoshana, 2012 (Box 65, Folder 32)
    - Research, Context, 2012 (Box 65, Folder 33)
    - Research, Interviews from the BAC Archive, 2012 (Box 65, Folder 34)
    - Research, Journal Entries, 2012 (Box 65, Folder 35)
    - Research, Rituals, 2012 (Box 65, Folder 36)
    - Research, Women from Past BAC Programs, 2012 (Box 65, Folder 37)
  - Sub-series 7.2: Audiovisual
    - Performance, Audio, 2012 (Box 66, Item 1)
    - Fieldwork, 2012 (Box 66, Item 2)
    - Events, Photographs, 2012 (Box 66, Item 3-11)
    - Events, Video, 2012 (Box 66, Item 12-31)
    - Interviews, Audio, 2012 (Box 66, Item 31-58)
- Series 8: Harborlore: Where the River Meets the Sea in Brooklyn's Folk Imagination
  Harborlore: Where the River Meets the Sea in Brooklyn's Folk Imagination was a series of twelve free dance, music and storytelling events throughout Brooklyn exploring the role of water in the artistic traditions of the borough's immigrant and diaspora communities post Hurricane Sandy.
  The program featured folk arts such as tashlich, a Rosh Hashanah (New Year) rite of renewal performed at the East River (among other places) by observant Jews; the life-size symbolic boats paraded at Scandinavian and Italian festivals in Bay Ridge and Williamsburg; the baptismal spirituals such as "Dip Them Leeward" sung in the African-Caribbean churches of East Flatbush; songs and chants sung in praise of water deities, such as the African-Brazilian mother of the ocean, Yemaja, and a fishing feast dance called hukila from Hawaii.
  Program Files include project expenses, funding and budget information, promotional materials, event planning documents and evaluation forms. The largest group in this sub-series includes press clippings, articles, notices of events, and other materials relating to the way in which water is considered in Brooklyn by its residents and government. Also included is material relating to climate change, Hurricane Sandy, and governmental policies pertaining to water and water use.
  The Audiovisual sub-series includes digital photographs, video, and audio documentation of Harborlore events. Also included is video interviews done in connection with the Harborlore project. See program files for interview releases and transcripts. Please note that not every interview includes a transcript.
  - Sub-series 8.1: Program Files
    - Expenses, 2013 (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - Funding, NEA Grant, 2013 (Box 67, Folder 2)
    - Publicity, 2013 (Box 67, Folder 3)
    - Oversize Posters, 2013 (Box 97, Folder 7)
    - Participants, Permissions, 2013 (Box 67, Folder 4)
    - Participants, Contracts, 2013 (Box 67, Folder 5)
    - Participants, Staff, 2013 (Box 67, Folder 6)
    - Core Artist Meeting, 2013 (Box 67, Folder 7)
    - Harborlore Opening Concert, Salute to Irving Burgie, 2013 (Box 67, Folder 8)
    - Sailing the Symbolic, Symposium on Brooklyn's Diverse Water Traditions, 2013 (Box 67, Folder 9)
    - Water in Brooklyn's Folk Imagination, 2013 (Box 67, Folder 10)
    - Bay Ridge Harbor Traditions Then and Now, Viking Fest, 2013 (Box 67, Folder 11)
    - Fish Tales, The Big One, The Magical One, The One That Got Away, 2013 (Box 67, Folder 12)
    - Hands Across the Harbor, 2013 (Box 67, Folder 13)
    - Songs of the Sea, Banana Boat Songs and Sea Shanties, 2013 (Box 67, Folder 14)
    - Danced Invocations for Red Hook Recovery, 2013 (Box 67, Folder 15)
    - Dancing in the Waters, 2013 (Box 67, Folder 16)
    - Tribute to Our Ancestors of the Middle Passage, 2013 (Box 67, Folder 17)
    - Sandylore Symposium, Cultural Knowledge as a Resource for Disaster Response, 2013 (Box 67, Folder 18)
    - Waterlore at Water's Edge, 2013 (Box 67, Folder 19)
    - Evaluations, 2013 (Box 67, Folder 20)
    - Supplementary Programs, 2013 (Box 67, Folder 21)
    - Arts and Crafts Exhibitors, 2013 (Box 67, Folder 22)
    - Boats and Boat Building, 2013 (Box 67, Folder 23)
    - City Planning and the Waterfront, 2013 (Box 67, Folder 24)
    - Research, Caribbean, 2013 (Box 67, Folder 25)
    - Research, Climate Change, 2013 (Box 67, Folder 26)
    - Research, Coastal Engineering, 2013 (Box 67, Folder 27)
    - Research, Dance, 2013 (Box 67, Folder 28)
    - Research, East River and NY Harbor, 2013 (Box 67, Folder 29)
    - Research, Film, 2013 (Box 67, Folder 30)
    - Research, The Harbor in the Media, 2013 (Box 67, Folder 31)
    - Research, Historic Ships, 2013 (Box 67, Folder 32)
    - Research, Hong Kong Dragon Boat Festival, 2013 (Box 67, Folder 33)
    - Research, Maps, 2013 (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - Research, Maritime Folklife Resources, 2013 (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - Context, Metropolitan Waterfront Alliance Annual Report, 2011 (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - Context, Metropolitan Waterfront Alliance Annual Report, 2012 (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - Context, Metropolitan Waterfront Alliance Annual Report, 2013 (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - Research, Museums and Nonprofits, 2013 (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - Research, Neighborhoods, 2013 (Box 68, Folder 7)
    - Research, Norwegians, 2013 (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - Research, Other Festivals and Programs, 2013 (Box 68, Folder 9)
    - Sailor's Valentines, 2013 (Box 68, Folder 10)
    - Research, Superstorm Sandy, 2013 (Box 68, Folder 11)
    - Research, Tashlich, Jewish Tradition at Rosh Hashanah, 2013 (Box 68, Folder 12)
    - Research, Water and Healing, 2013 (Box 68, Folder 13)
    - Research, Water Festivals, 2013 (Box 68, Folder 14)
    - Research, Waterway Rides, 2013 (Box 68, Folder 15)
    - Research, Workers- Longshoremen, Sand Hogs, Ferryboat Men, 2013 (Box 68, Folder 16)
    - Research, Yemen, Fishing Songs, 2013 (Box 68, Folder 17)
    - Interviews, Transcript: James Lovell, 2013 (Box 68, Folder 18)
    - Interviews, Transcripts: George Davidson, 2013 (Box 68, Folder 19)
    - Interviews, Transcript: Winston "Jeggae" Hoppie, 2013 (Box 68, Folder 20-21)
    - Interview, Transcript: E. Wayne McDonald, 2013 (Box 68, Folder 22)
    - Interview, Transcript: Gabriella Dennery, 2013 (Box 68, Folder 23)
  - Sub-series 8.2: Audiovisual
    Harborlore Core Artist Meeting May 5, 2013.
    Sailing the Symbolic: Symposium of Brooklyn's Diverse Water Traditions Brooklyn Public Library, Central Branch, Dweck Auditorium, May 11, 2013.
    Bay Ridge Harbor Traditions Then and Now Held at Viking Festival, Owl's Head Park/Bliss Park, May 18, 2013.
    Hands Across the Harbor Snug Harbor Cultural Center, Staten Island, May 25, 2013.
    Songs of the Sea: Banana Boat Songs and Sea Shanties Jalopy Music Theatre, Red Hook, May 30, 2013.
    Danced Invocations for Red Hook Recovery Held at the 20th annual Red Hook Fest, Coffey and Ferris Streets, Red Hook June 1, 2013.
    Dancing the Waters Kaiser Park, Coney Island, June 2, 2013.
    Sandylore Symposium: Cultural Knowledge as a Resource for Disaster Response The Actors fund Center, Downtown Brooklyn, June 13, 2013.
    Waterlore at the Water's Edge Brooklyn Bridge Park, June 15, 2013.
    Interviews:
    Aeilushi Mistry, January 22, 2013
    James Lovell, February 9, 2013
    George Davidson, Guyana water lore, February 15, 2013
    Wrichford "Rich" Dalgetty, February 22, 2013
    Seetha Wickramasuriya, October 10, 2013
    Annie Fedous, Bangladeshi vessel dance, October 18, 2012
    Nisha Hettiarachchi, no date
    E. Wayne McDonald, July 2, 2013
    Gabriella Dennery, July 12, 2013
    - Events, Photographs, 2013 (Box 69, Item 1)
    - Events, Video, 2013 (Box 69, Item 2-55)
    - Interviews, 2013 (Box 69, Item 56-65)
    - Additional Media, 2013 (Box 69, Item 66-67)
- Series 9: Local Eyes: Folk Photographers Documenting Brooklyn
  Local Eyes: Folk Photographers Documenting Brooklyn was a project that concluded with a photograph exhibit presented at the Five Myles gallery in Crown Heights from May 17-June 15, 2002. The exhibit focused on Brooklyn photographers who documented people and events within their own communities, including rituals and traditions of family and community life. The exhibit was produced by Kay Turner, Folks Arts Director of the Brooklyn Arts Council.
  Program Files include information about project expenses, funding, publicity, and items that document the mounting of the exhibition. Also included are files relating to the photographers who participated in the exhibit. Files hold printed photographs, correspondence, and some audio interviews. This series has no audiovisual sub-series.
  Participating photographers and their subjects:
  Anthony Bonair, West Indian Parade. Includes interview.
  Anthony Cimino, Williamsburg, giglio. Includes interview.
  William deMeritte, dancers.
  Mel Gerson, Coney Island.
  Anders Goldfarb, Greenpoint
  Irving Herzberg, Hasidic Brooklyn.
  John Huang, Chinese New Year.
  Helen Marrero, Fort Greene. See folder for Anthony Cimino for interview.
  Cliff Matias, Indigenous pow wow.
  Angie Picolo, Park Slope: Includes interview.
  Luis Rodriguez, Borough Park, no file.
  - Sub-series 9.1: Program Files
    - Notes, 2002 (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, Photographers, 2002 (Box 70, Folder 2)
    - Photographers, 2002 (Box 70, Folder 3)
    - Expenses, 2002 (Box 70, Folder 4)
    - Funding, NYSCA, 2002 (Box 70, Folder 5)
    - Press Releases, 2002 (Box 70, Folder 6)
    - Flyer, Soliciting Entrants, 2002 (Box 70, Folder 7)
    - Postcard, 2002 (Box 70, Folder 8)
    - Press Clippings, 2002 (Box 70, Folder 9)
    - Anthony Bonair, 2002 (Box 70, Folder 10)
    - Anthony Cimino, 2002 (Box 70, Folder 11)
    - William DeMeritte, 2002 (Box 70, Folder 12)